Guide to the Jack Metcalf Papers 1973-2001
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Congressional Career, 1984-2001; 1995-2000; Series II
  - Washington D.C. Office files, 1984-2001; (bulk 1995-2000); Subseries 1
    - Legislative Issues, 1984-2001
      - Banking and Investment, 1990-2000; (bulk 1997-2000)
        - Alaska Community Development Quota Program (publicity at Seattle Fish Exposition), 1999 (Box-folder 4/7)
        - Bank Reserves Modernization (H.R. 4209), 2000 (Box-folder 4/8)
        - Business finance
          - Business Checking Modernization Act (H.R. 4067), 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4/9)
          - House Committee on Small Business – recess packet, 1997 (Box-folder 4/10)
          - House Committee on Small Business – recess packet, 1999 (Box-folder 4/11)
          - National Federation of Independent Business- member ballot, 1999 (Box-folder 4/12)
          - National Federation of Independent Business – recess packet, 1999 (Box-folder 4/13)
          - National Federation of Independent Business – tax relief campaign, 1999 (Box-folder 4/14)
          - Regulatory Right-to-Know Act (H.R. 1074), 1999 (Box-folder 4/15)
          - Small Business Banking Act, 1996-2000; undated (Box-folder 4/16 - 4/17)
          - Small Business Banking Act – community bank survey, 1998 (Box-folder 4/18 - 4/19)
          - Small Business Development Center – information packet, 1998 (Box-folder 4/20)
          - Small Businesses and Health Care, 1999 (Box-folder 4/21)
          - Small Business Innovation Research program, circa 2000 (Box-folder 4/22)
          - Small Business reports, 1994 (Box-folder 4/23)
        - China – Permanent Normal Trade Relations, 2000 (Box-folder 4/24)
        - Conference: Rethinking Banking Regulation, 1996 (Box-folder 4/25)
        - Consumer Mortgage Protection Act, 2000 (Box-folder 4/26)
        - Currency Circulation (H.R. 5510), 2000 (Box-folder 4/27)
        - Debt, 2000 (Box-folder 4/28)
        - Electronic Signature Bill, 2000 (Box-folder 4/29)
        - Fair Debt Bill, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 4/30)
        - Federal and State/Local Fiscal Data, circa 1998-2000 (Box-folder 4/31)
        - Federal Reserve System
          - Committee reports and hearings, circa 1995-1998 (Box-folder 4/32)
          - Federal Reserve Board of Governors’ Annual Report, 1999 (Box-folder 4/33)
          - Federal Reserve Bill (draft), 2000 (Box-folder 4/34)
          - Federal Reserve Publications, 1998 (Box-folder 4/35)
          - Reports, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 4/36)
          - Speech to House, undated (Box-folder 4/37)
        - Financial Investments Institute, 1996 (Box-folder 4/38)
        - International Financial Institutions (reports to Banking Committee), 2000 (Box-folder 5/1)
        - Levy Institute / Infrastructure Financing, 1994; 1999 (Box-folder 5/2)
        - Levy Plan (State and local capital projects), 1995-1999 (Box-folder 5/3)
        - Multilateral Development Banks: World Bank, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 5/4)
        - Multilateral Agreement on Investment, 1998 (Box-folder 5/5)
        - National Security Transportation Emergency Investment, circa 2000 (Box-folder 5/6)
        - Newspaper Clippings re: Banking issues, 2000 (Box-folder 5/7)
        - Taxation
          - Balanced Budget Act and Tax Relief, 1997 (Box-folder 5/8)
          - Death Tax Elimination Act, 1999 (Box-folder 5/9)
          - Marriage Penalty Elimination Act, 1999 (Box-folder 5/10)
          - Tax Relief: Talking Points, 1999 (Box-folder 5/11)
          - Top Ten Tax Changes, 1999 (Box-folder 5/12)
        - Trade Adjustment Assistance Program, 2000 (Box-folder 5/13)
        - U.S. Census: Department of Commerce reports, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 5/14)
        - U.S. Chamber of Commerce “Spirit of Enterprise” award, 2000 (Box-folder 5/15)
        - U.S. Mint
          - One Dollar Coin proposals, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 5/16)
          - Sacagawea Golden Dollar Coin – Distribution, 1999 (Box-folder 5/17)
          - Sacagawea Golden Dollar Coin – Background Information & Opposition Response, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 5/18)
      - Campaigns and Elections, 1998-1999
        An advocate of campaign finance reform and Congressional term limits, Metcalf supported the Shays-Meehan Campaign Finance Reform bill, passed by the House of Representatives in 1998.
        - Campaign Finance Reform, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 5/19 - 5/20)
        - US Term Limits – press clippings, 1999 (Box-folder 5/21)
        - US Term Limits – press releases, 1999 (Box-folder 5/22)
        - US Term Limits – reports and background, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 5/23)
      - Defense and US Military, 1991-2001; (bulk 1995-2001)
        Defense and US military files reflect Metcalf’s active interest in local and national military affairs. Subject files document his opposition to Clinton’s use of executive authority to deploy troops in Kosovo (culminating in his introduction of a War Powers Bill in 1999), support for Boeing’s 1995 bid to supply a ‘mixed fleet’ of C-17 and Boeing 747 aircraft to the US Air Force, and a small amount of material regarding his investigations into causes of Gulf War Illnesses. In 1997, Metcalf introduced House Resolution 191, condemning European Union opposition to the merger of Boeing Co. and McDonnell Douglas. Files also include brochures and press kits from US Navy vessels and stations visited by Jeff Markey, Metcalf’s military liaison assistant.
        - Arlington National Cemetery, 1997 (Box-folder 5/24)
        - Boeing-McDonnell Douglas Merger (House Resolution 191), undated (Box-folder 5/25)
        - Boeing – B-52H program, circa 1997 (Box-folder 5/26)
        - Boeing - F-22 program, circa 1997 (Box-folder 5/27)
        - Boeing - V-22 Osprey Tiltrotor, 1994 (Box-folder 5/28)
        - Boeing – Washington State Delegation Staff Briefing, 1997 (Box-folder 5/29)
        - Bosnia – Floor speech, 1995 (Box-folder 5/30)
        - Bosnia – Floor speech background material, 1995 (Box-folder 5/31)
        - Bosnia – motion to instruct (clerk), circa 1995 (Box-folder 5/32)
        - Bosnia – motion to withhold funding (Metcalf), 1995 (Box-folder 5/33)
        - Bosnia – motion to withhold funding, 1995 (Box-folder 5/34)
        - Bosnia – Rules Committee, 1995 (Box-folder 5/35)
        - Bosnia – White House policy, 1995 (Box-folder 5/36)
        - Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty, 1999 (Box-folder 5/37)
        - Defense Budget FY 2001, circa 2000 (Box-folder 5/38)
        - Discovery Institute, 1999 (Box-folder 5/39)
        - EA-6B Prowler, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 5/40 - 5/41)
        - Heritage Foundation Candidate Briefings (Defense), circa 2000 (Box-folder 5/42)
        - House Armed Services Committee Defense Report, 1999 (Box-folder 5/43)
        - Intermec Technologies Corporation FY 1999 Programs, circa 1998 (Box-folder 5/44)
        - Intermec Technologies Corporation FY 2000 Programs, circa 1999 (Box-folder 5/45)
        - Intermec Technologies Corporation FY 2001 Programs, circa 2000 (Box-folder 6/1)
        - International Space Station, circa 1997 (Box-folder 6/2)
        - Iran Non-proliferation Act / Space Stations, 1999 (Box-folder 6/3)
        - Kinetic Energy Anti-Satellite Program, 1997 (Box-folder 6/4)
        - Kosovo Strategy, 1999 (Box-folder 6/5)
        - Military Case files, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 6/6 - 6/10)
        - Missile Defense (H.R. 4), 1999 (Box-folder 6/11)
        - Mobility Requirements Study, 1992 (Box-folder 6/12)
        - Mukilteo Tank Farm, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 6/13)
        - National Guard Association – Legislative Priorities, 2001 (Box-folder 6/14)
        - National Guard (Washington) – Activities and funding, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 6/15)
        - National Guard (Washington) – proposed restructuring, 1998 (Box-folder 6/16)
        - National Guard (Washington) – Sedro Woolley Armory, 1997 (Box-folder 6/17)
        - National Guard (Washington) – Yakima Training Center, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 6/18 - 6/19)
        - National Security Agency, 2000 (Box-folder 6/20)
        - Non-Developmental Airlift Aircraft (NDAA) program
          - Affordable Airlift Act, 1996 (Box-folder 6/21)
          - Background articles, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 6/22)
          - Boeing Bid, 1995 (Box-folder 6/23)
          - C-17 Aircraft, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 6/24)
          - Correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 6/25)
          - Impact on Civil Reserve Air Fleet, 1995 (Box-folder 6/26)
          - Language, 1995 (Box-folder 6/27)
          - Press clippings, 1995 (Box-folder 6/28)
          - Talking Points, 1995 (Box-folder 6/29)
        - Quadrenniel Defense Review 6/31 6/32, 1997 (Box-folder 6/30)
        - Seawulf Submarine, 1995 (Box-folder 6/31)
        - Smithway Co. (steam piping systems), 1991; 1996 (Box-folder 6/32)
        - US Air Force
          - Air Force Association, 1995; 2000 (Box-folder 6/33)
          - Air Force Reserve, 1995 (Box-folder 6/34)
          - Brochures and Profiles, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 6/35-6/36)
        - US Army – profiles, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 6/37)
        - US Navy bases and vessels
          - Everett Naval Station - reductions and base closures, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 7/1)
          - Everett Naval Station / Whidbey Island - Military Construction Appropriations, circa 1997-1999 (Box-folder 7/2)
          - San Diego Naval Base, undated (Box-folder 7/3)
          - Seattle Naval Base, 1995 (Box-folder 7/4)
          - Submarine base Bangor, undated (Box-folder 7/5)
          - Submarine program, undated (Box-folder 7/6)
          - USS America, 1995 (Box-folder 7/7)
          - USS Essex, undated (Box-folder 7/8)
          - USS Gettysburg, 1995 (Box-folder 7/9)
          - USS Henry M. Jackson, undated (Box-folder 7/10)
          - USS Pennsylvania, 1995 (Box-folder 7/11)
          - USS Wilber Curtis, undated (Box-folder 7/12)
          - Whidbey Island Naval Air Station, 1995 – 1996 (Box-folder 7/13 - 7/14)
          - Whidbey Island Naval Air Station – Family Service Center, 1996 (Box-folder 7/15)
          - Whidbey Island Navy Search and Rescue Unit, 1996 (Box-folder 7/16)
          - Whidbey Island “V.R.” Squadrons, 1996 (Box-folder 7/17)
        - US Navy carrier aviation, undated (Box-folder 7/18)
        - US Navy condolence letters, 1996 (Box-folder 7/19)
        - US Navy conference, 1997 (Box-folder 7/20)
        - US Navy guides and strategic reports, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 7/21)
        - US Navy Special Warfare, undated (Box-folder 7/22)
        - US Navy suppliers – Lister Chain and Forge Inc., 1995-1997 (Box-folder 7/23)
        - Veterans' Issues
          - Clipping re: deceased veteran files, 2000 (Box-folder 7/24)
          - Gulf War Illnesses - briefings and legislative proposals, 1997 (Box-folder 7/25)
          - Gulf War Illnesses – General Accounting Office report, 1999 (Box-folder 7/26)
          - Gulf War Illnesses – Newspaper clipping, 2000 (Box-folder 7/27)
          - HMT Rohna, 2000 (Box-folder 7/28)
          - Homeless Veterans Assistance Act (H.R. 1008), 1999-2000 (Box-folder 7/29)
          - Robert Stodola Homeless Veterans Assistance Act (H.R. 1754), 1997 (Box-folder 7/30)
          - Tricare (Military Health Care), 1999 (Box-folder 7/31)
          - Veterans Affairs, correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 7/32)
          - Veterans Affairs/Housing and Urban Development - funding, 2000 (Box-folder 7/33)
          - Veteran Appraisal Process, 2000 (Box-folder 7/34)
        - War Powers resolution, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 7/35)
        - War Powers Act, 1999 (Box-folder 7/36 - 7/37)
      - Education, circa 1996 - 2000
        Education files document Metcalf’s interest in securing federal and state funds for schools in naval home ports in Washington State, including Marysville and Everett. Correspondence and statements regarding Higher Education Amendments reflect conflict over attempts to limit affirmative action and equal opportunity programs in colleges and universities. A small amount of material pertains to the Lummi Indian Nation’s efforts to gain funding for a new tribal school.
        - Academic Achievement for All (Straight A’s Act), 1999 (Box-folder 8/1)
        - Agenda for the American Learner, 1998 (Box-folder 8/2)
        - Bilingual Eduation, 1998 (Box-folder 8/3)
        - Child Care, 1998 (Box-folder 8/4)
        - Community Services Block Grant, 1997 (Box-folder 8/5)
        - Congressional Research Service – Impact Aid Program, 1991 (Box-folder 8/6)
        - Congressional Research Service – Impact Aid Program/Marysville, 1996 (Box-folder 8/7)
        - Dollars to the Classroom (H.R. 3248), 1998 (Box-folder 8/8)
        - Education Briefing, 1999 March 8 (Box-folder 8/9)
        - Education Flexibility Partnership Act (H.R. 800), 1999 (Box-folder 8/10)
        - Education Loans, 1999 (Box-folder 8/11)
        - Education Talking Points, 1999 (Box-folder 8/12)
        - Everett – Navy Home Port Funding (SHB 611), 1997 (Box-folder 8/13)
        - Everett – Navy Station Housing Environmental Assessment, 1996 (Box-folder 8/14 - 8/15)
        - Higher Education Amendments (H.R. 6), 1998 (Box-folder 8/16 - 8/18)
        - Impact Aid Bill, 1998 (Box-folder 8/19)
        - Impact Aid Letters, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 8/20)
        - Kaptur Amendment, 1997 (Box-folder 8/21)
        - Labor- Health and Human Services – Education appropriations bill, 1997 (Box-folder 8/22)
        - Lakewood Post Office, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 8/23)
        - Lummi Tribal School, 1997-1998; 2000 (Box-folder 8/24)
        - Lummi Tribal School/American Indian Higher Education Consortium, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8/25)
        - Marysville School District, 1995-1996; 1999 (Box-folder 8/26)
        - Military Dependent Children (Oak Harbor), 1992-1997 (Box-folder 8/27)
        - Military Housing – Public/Private Partnership, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 8/28)
        - National Testing, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 8/29)
        - School Choice, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 8/30)
        - Seattle Schools, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 8/31)
        - Teacher Empowerment Act (H.R. 1995), 1999 (Box-folder 8/32)
        - University of Washington, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 8/33)
        - Washington State Legislature – proposed legislation, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 8/34)
        - Western Washington University – Education Grant, 2000 (Box-folder 8/35)
      - Energy, 1996-2000
        Energy files document disputes between Puget Sound power providers Bonneville Power Administration and Puget Sound Energy, and local customers including ARCO. A small amount of material pertains to restoration projects and treatment of radioactive waste at Hanford in southeastern Washington.
        - ARCO-Puget Sound Energy Dispute, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9/1)
        - Bonneville Power Administration – Corporate Citizenship Clause, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 9/2)
        - Bonneville Power Administration – Customer relations, 1998 (Box-folder 9/3)
        - Bonneville Power Administration – power sales contract signing suspension, 2000 (Box-folder 9/4)
        - Bonneville Power Administration – Subscription proposal, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9/5)
        - Bonneville Power Administration – Transmission / Generator separation, 1997 (Box-folder 9/6)
        - Department of Energy policy, 1997 (Box-folder 9/7)
        - Department of Energy restructuring, 1999 (Box-folder 9/8)
        - Electricity Deregulation, 1997 (Box-folder 9/9)
        - Electricity Industry Restructuring Survey, 1997 (Box-folder 9/10)
        - Federal/Statewide Electricity Activities, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9/11)
        - Grant County WA Public Utilities District, 1996 (Box-folder 9/12)
        - Hanford Plutonium Disposition, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9/13)
        - Hanford Reach Restoration, 1996 (Box-folder 9/14)
        - Hydro Energy Development Company, 1999 (Box-folder 9/15)
        - Northwest Energy Delegation, 1997 (Box-folder 9/16)
        - Northwest Power Planning, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 9/17 - 9/18)
        - Nuclear Waste Policy, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 9/19)
        - Orcas Power and Light Company, 1997 (Box-folder 9/20)
        - “Private Use” restrictions on public power bonds, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9/21)
        - Snohomish County WA Public Utilities District, 2000 (Box-folder 9/22)
        - Whatcom County WA Public Utilities District / Puget Sound Energy Dispute, 2000 (Box-folder 9/23)
      - Executive Branch, 1994-2000
        - Executive Orders - articles and reports, 1999 (Box-folder 9/24)
        - Executive Orders - Clinton history, 2000 (Box-folder 9/25)
        - Executive Orders – Executive Order Limitation Act (H.R. 3131), 1999 (Box-folder 9/26)
        - Executive Orders – Hearing materials, 2000 (Box-folder 9/27)
        - Executive Orders – House Congressional Resolution 30, 1999 (Box-folder 9/28 - 9/29)
        - Executive Orders - House Congressional Resolution 236, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9/30)
        - Executive Orders – Metcalf resolution (untitled), 1999 (Box-folder 9/31)
        - Executive Orders – Presidential Decision Directive 25, circa 1994-1998 (Box-folder 9/32)
        - Executive Orders –Separation of Powers Restoration Act (H.R. 2655), 1999 (Box-folder 9/33)
      - Fishing and Salmon, 1984-2000; (bulk 1996-2000)
        Fishing and Salmon files document both the down-turn in the region’s fishing industry at the end of the twentieth century, and ongoing debates and conflicts regarding the conservation of salmon and other fish in the Pacific Northwest, notably in the Columbia and Snake Rivers. Records reflect Metcalf’s support for fish and crab license buy-back programs, and his later attempts to secure federal emergency aid for Washington fishers adversely affected by the collapse of the sockeye fishing season in 1999.
        - Bonneville Power Administration, 1999 (Box-folder 9/34)
        - Canadian Salmon, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9/35)
        - Columbia Basin Fish – 4H Recovery Plan, 1999 (Box-folder 9/36)
        - Columbia River – John Day Dam Drawdown, 1997 (Box-folder 9/37)
        - Commerce Subcommittee on Justice, 1998 (Box-folder 9/38)
        - Crab Buyback Program - Senate appropriations, 1997 (Box-folder 9/39)
        - Crab/Shellfish Buyback Program, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 9/40)
        - Dam Removal, 1999 (Box-folder 9/41)
        - Endangered Species Act (ESA) – Section 4(d) rules, 2000 (Box-folder 9/42)
        - ESA compliance – agriculture, 1999 (Box-folder 9/43)
        - ESA compliance – Washington Forests and Fish agreement, 1999 (Box-folder 10/1)
        - ESA general information, 1990 (Box-folder 10/2)
        - ESA language – NW salmon as Evolutionary Significant Units, 1999 (Box-folder 10/3)
        - Fisheries – Halibut and Sablefish, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 10/4)
        - Fishing Buyback Program, 1997 (Box-folder 10/5)
        - Fishing Vessel Atlantic Star, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 10/6)
        - Fishing Vessel Fierce Contender, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 10/7)
        - Fish Passage/Washington State Department of Transportation, 1997 (Box-folder 10/8)
        - Gilcrest Fisheries Recovery Bill, 2000 (Box-folder 10/9)
        - Haskell Slough, Monroe WA, 1999 (Box-folder 10/10)
        - Icicle Seafood - Hoard nomination, 1997 (Box-folder 10/11)
        - Illegal Driftnetting, 1999 (Box-folder 10/12)
        - Individual Fishing Quotas, 2000 (Box-folder 10/13)
        - Initiative 456 (Washington State), 1984 (Box-folder 10/14)
        - Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 10/15)
        - Mitchell Act Funding, 1999 (Box-folder 10/16)
        - Mitchell Act – Hatcheries, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 10/17)
        - National Marine Fisheries Service – Funding, 1999 (Box-folder 10/18)
        - National Sea Grant College Program, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 10/19)
        - North Pacific Fisheries Management Council appointments, 1999 (Box-folder 10/20)
        - Pacific Northwest Commercial Fisheries, 1997 (Box-folder 10/21)
        - Pacific Salmon lawsuits, 1999 (Box-folder 10/22)
        - Pacific Salmon Treaty, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 10/23-10/24)
        - Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission – FY 1998 appropriations proposal, 1997 (Box-folder 10/25)
        - Predation on Salmon (aviation) – Lower Columbia River, 1998 (Box-folder 10/26)
        - Predation on Salmon (pinniped) – Marine Mammal Removal, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 10/27)
        - Puget Sound Ecosystem Recovery Initiative, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 10/28)
        - Salmon Conservation – ESA listings, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 10/29)
        - Salmon Recovery – Local and State Government response, 1999 (Box-folder 10/30)
        - Salmon Recovery Funding Board, 2000 (Box-folder 10/31)
        - Salmon Restoration, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 10/32 - 10/33)
        - Salmon Restoration appropriations FY 2001, 2000 (Box-folder 10/34)
        - Salmon Restoration proposals – Tribal response, 1999 (Box-folder 10/35)
        - Salmon Volunteer project, 1999 (Box-folder 10/36)
        - Sierra Club Pacific Northwest Wild Salmon Campaign, 1998 (Box-folder 10/37)
        - Skagit Agricultural Buffer, circa 1999 (Box-folder 10/38)
        - Stellar Sea Lions / Alaska Pollock Fisheries, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 10/39)
        - Tanner Fishable Waters Act, 2000 (Box-folder 10/40)
        - Washington Farmed Salmon Commission, 1997 (Box-folder 10/41)
        - Washington State Governor’s Disaster Declaration, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 10/42)
        - Washington State Legislature, 1999 (Box-folder 10/43)
        - Washington State Tri-County ESA response, 1998 (Box-folder 10/44)
        - Western Wood Preservers’ Institute – ESA Regulations, 1999 (Box-folder 10/45)
      - Ground Transportation, 1995-2001
        Ground Transportation files include background information and funding proposals for a variety of transportation improvement and development projects in the Puget Sound region of Washington. As a member of the House Transportation and Infrastructure Committee, and Ground Transportation subcommittee, Metcalf was actively involved in securing funds to develop and improve regional roads, bridges, transportation centers, port access, border crossings, and rail and bus mass transit systems. The majority of these projects sought funding from grants available under the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act, renewed by Congress in 1998.
        - Amtrak Cascades – Fast Facts/Funding, undated (Box-folder 11/1)
        - Amtrak Cascades – Vancouver BC to Seattle (second roundtrip), 2000 (Box-folder 11/2)
        - Amtrak Reform Council – Preliminary Assessment, 2000 (Box-folder 11/3)
        - Budget Appropriations (Puget Sound Transportation), 2000-2001 (Box-folder 11/4)
        - Burlington Northern Santa Fe – Everett Bayside operation noise, 1997 (Box-folder 11/5)
        - Burlington Northern Santa Fe railroad – Stampede Pass, 1997 (Box-folder 11/6)
        - Canadian National/Burlington Northern Santa Fe merger, 2000 (Box-folder 11/7)
        - Central Puget Sound Regional Transit Authority (Sound Transit)
          - Citizen Oversight Panel, 1997 (Box-folder 11/8)
          - Light Rail Project, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 11/9)
          - Lobbyist material, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11/10)
          - Sound Move Plan, 1997 (Box-folder 11/11 - 11/12)
        - Coalition for TRUST, 1999 (Box-folder 11/13)
        - Committee on Transportation & Infrastructure – subcommittee jurisdictions, undated (Box-folder 11/14)
        - Community Transit (Snohomish County), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 11/15)
        - Deception Pass Bridge, 2000 (Box-folder 11/16)
        - Department of Transportation FY 2000 Budget, 1999 (Box-folder 11/17)
        - Everett Combined Sewer Overflow (CSO) Project Outline, 1999 (Box-folder 11/18)
        - Everett I-5 Corridor Design Report and Environmental Impact Study, 1997 (Box-folder 11/19)
        - Everett I-5 Corridor projects, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 11/20)